大师兄 小心点
Brother, watch out.
知道了
Don't worry
这个金狮在这儿吃惯住惯的
The golden lion belongs to this school
自已都知道回来了
he's never going to leave, right?
年年都是这样拿出去摆个样子
Because of him no one's gonna beat us!
还不是又赢回来
You can say that again!
喂 想偷懒呀
Come on! Do some work!
我不是在干着活吗
But l am working!
手脚俐落点
Looks like it!
准备好了没有
Everything ready?
准备好了
Yes, master!
衣服都送来了吗
Are the costumes here?
霞姐等一回就送来
No, sister Har is bringing them over
师父 上海婆来了
Master, sister Har's arrived
我是赶得及的
Hello there, master!
上海婆上海婆
Hello, sister...
麻烦你了
Hello everyone! Hi...
衣服都来了
l finished your costumes at last
要穿新衣服快点来拿去
Come try them on, everyone!
大家自已看清楚 不要弄错呀
Make sure you have the right one, don't mix them up
各人拿各人的
Make sure you have the right costume
你来拿
Come on, hurry up!
龙哥
Brother Lung!
我就来了
l'll be right there!
大师兄 你衣服在这儿
Here, brother! Here's your costume!
大师兄
Brother...
What's happening?
大师兄
Are you alright?
怎么样
What happened? You alright?
我的脚好痛呀
My leg really hurts!
谁把木桶放在这里
Which idiot put the bucket there?
一定是野孩子
lt must have been the orphan
我
Me?
快点扶我起来
Hurry, get me up will you?
快扶他起来
Help him up!
快扶他坐下
Somebody give him a chair!
你怎么做事的 还要你舞狮头
This really couldn't have come at a worse time
大师兄不能舞狮头 这回输定了
Brother Jing's supposed to carry the lion's head!
没有大师兄就没有人会舞狮吗
Without him, you think we'll lose, right?
还有我嘛
But l'm here!
轮到我也轮不到你
l was here before you!
不要吵
Yeah, l know that!
看情形要换个人舞狮头了
lt looks like we'll need a replacement
我 师父 我不行
Me, master? l couldn't...
你当然不行
No, l didn't mean you!
阿龙 你来
Well, Lung?
野孩子怎么行呢
Lung's not good enough to do it!
他不行 我来呀
lf he isn't, then l'll do it!
我来才对
No, you won't. l was...
别吵
You two! Be quiet!
准备出狮
Lung will do it
各位观众 在过去的一年
Citizens and fellow villagers
本镇风调雨顺 人口平安
this year has brought us peace and renewed prosperity
所谓有例不可废 今年我们
ln accordance with our tradition
特别准备了一个水陆平安青
we've created a token symbolizing peace in our land
由本镇的正风武馆和
The Jing Fung and Wai Yee martial arts schools
威义武馆比赛采青
will be competing for the token
看那家武馆给我们带来好运的一年
We will see which school brings us good luck for the coming year
什么平安青呀
What kind of token's that?
面青
lt's a green token
什么
What?
如果叫我去采 面也青
lf l don't get it then l'm gonna turn green!
这个叫做盘龙八卦青
lt's the 8 Circling Dragons token
这只狮舞得好生动
We've got all the right moves
厉害罢
Yeah, they're good!
这只狮舞得好生动
They've got a good team this year
步履和身形都不像是威义堂的人
They have some different techniques this year
阿龙 你舞狮头 是
- Are you ready, Lung? - Yes
阿灿 你舞狮尾 是
- Chan, you get the tail - Yes
大家准备
Everyone gets ready
你打鼓
Man the drum!
你买什么 当然买黑狮
- What's your bet? - On the black lion
怎么会买黑狮的
lt won't win
我希望爆冷呀
But l'm rich if it does!
什么盘口
What are the odds?
黑狮一赔十
10 to 1 for the black
金狮就一块赔五毛
For the gold, 2 to 1 on
那我岂不是输定五毛
2 to 1 on?
我也知道是金狮赢定啦
We all know gold will win
如果大家都买金狮 我连老婆都赔啦
l'd be crazy to give any better odds
那些表格难道不要钱印的
Good day, l have a business to run
我买黑狮
l'll take the black
去排队
Just go wait in line
什么 你买黑狮
Wait! Did you say black?
对呀 那不用排队了
- Yes. - Then no need to line up
我替你填表
l'll fill out your ticket right now
跳过去呀
Go on! You can do it!
怎么办
What should we do?
敢不敢跳过去 敢
- Think you can do it? - Sure
掀尾巴
Lift up the tail!
没桥怎么过去呀
They're never gonna do that
上
Go for it!...
别让他上去
All right! Keep going!...
别让他上去 打他
Go on! Get up there!
别让他上去 千万别让他上去
Keep pushing, brother!
打他 打他
Push...
顶硬上
Keep going!
阿灿 绑腰带
Chan! Your belt!
好
Right!
绑好了没有
Chan! Are you ready?
绑好了
l'm all right!
我下去啦
Here l go!
大师兄
Brother?
少废话 有本事就抢好了
We're not brothers! You want it you take it!
大师兄 你
But...
上了
Go!...
别放手呀
Don't let go!
大师兄 你为什么这样做
Why are you doing this, brother?
到底为什么呢
Why?
现在各为其主
lt's not in the rules!
你别当我是大师兄了
Forget the rules. l was paid to win this!
把本事拿出来吧
And that's what l'm gonna do!
这不是为难我吗
Come on, don't do this!
顶住 顶住呀
Look out! Hold him up!...
不要吵 快点抢青
Shut up! Get the token!
快抢 抢呀
Get the token!...
我们赢了
Yeah! We won!...
舅父 替我们舞头的真行
Who was doing the head? He was really something!
你在那里找的
Where do you get him?
不要问了 快去捧金狮 去
Alright, don't just stand there! Go and collect the gold lion!
好了 快收拾东西回去
Alright, clean up everything!
还不快下来
Don't just sit there!
我赢了 我去拿钱
l have to collect my winnings!
都是你呀 害得我输钱
You idiots! l lost a fortune! You're no good!
我做黑狮 你做金狮 来呀
You be the black lion, l'll be the gold lion!
你点点看 不会亏待你的
You check it. l don't want complaints
我们是一次生两次熟
Good accounting makes good friends
等土地公公生日再来帮忙
And we'll do the same thing next year
做得多了 会露出马脚的
Someone's gonna find out
露就露好了
Then why don't you do as l said
你到我这儿来给个教头你做好了
and come and teach at our school?
回去想想看
What about it?
我回去考虑考虑
l'll think it over
师父 输了还是赢了
Master, did we win it?
输
Mas...
输了就输了 愁眉苦脸干什么
Alright, we lost. lt's in the past now
还不快点练功
Get back to practice!
阿龙
Lung!
你耍狮头连狮头都抓不稳
You can't even hold the lion's head
搬桌子举一百下
For your punishment
练练你的手劲
you'll lift the table 100 times!
替我把席擦一擦好吗
Will you scrub my bed for me?
替你擦擦那谁替我擦呀
Who do you think l am, your servant?
动手擦吧
Oh, come on!
现在又不是请你来做大少爷
Yeah, dream on, brother!
擦 自已擦吧
Get on with it!
又是那挡子事呀
What? Again?
叫你去就去啦 快去
Just do what l say. Go on!
那边
That way
知道啦 进房去嘛
Don't worry, l know the way
我又不是第一次来
This isn't the first time
别那么大声 师父刚睡呀
Not so loud! The master's in the bedroom
去外边又怕人家看见
lf you're so embarrassed about it
在里边又怕师父知道
and so afraid that your master will find out
胆子那么小就别学人家风流
why did you bother bringing me here?
我来了
Hello handsome! Me again!
大师兄
Brother
什么事啊
What's the matter?
怎么又是她呀
lt's she again?
你先出去
Never mind about that!
大师兄 你可别那么久呀
Brother, don't take too long!
知道啦 你先出去 出去
Let me worry about that. Now get out of here!
来啊 陪我玩
Come on! Play with me
起来 死胖子
Come on
糟了 师父来了
Look out! Master's here!
师父
Master!
你干什么
What are you doing?
没什么 这儿凉快嘛
lt's much cooler in here
这儿凉快
Cooler in here?
对呀
That's right!
你想闷死我吗
You're suffocating me!
不是
No, no...
你干什么 你想揩油呀
What do you think you're doing?
揩油
Nothing!
师父 我下次不敢啦
Master, l won't do it again!
还有下次
l'll make sure you don't!
干什么呀你 走
- Get off me! - Get out!
这里是武馆 不是妓院 快走
This is a school, not a brothel. Get out!
走就走 又不是什么好地方
Don't worry l'm not wasting any more time here
看什么 没见过女人呀
What's up? Never seen a girl before?
把裤腰带给我
Lung, give me your belt
威义堂
Wai Yee School?
说 威义堂为什么给你钱
Why did they give you this money?
为什么
Tell me! Why?
我 说
- Me... - Speak up!
说不说 快说
What did you do for this?
拿来 拿来
Tell me! Tell me!
阿强
Jing Keung?
Keung
威义堂为什么要给你钱
Why did the Wai Yee School pay you?
你替他做过些什么
What did you do for them?
他没跟你说我帮威义堂舞狮吗
Didn't Lung tell you? l danced for Wai Yee School
我没说 大师兄 你们走开
- l didn't say anything, l didn't! - Get out
你出去
Get out!
大师兄
Brother..
出去 出去
l said out! All of you!
师父
Master..
你还有脸叫我师父
How dare you call me your master?
你这个没出息吃里扒外的东西
Don't you realize what you've done? You've betrayed the school!
你还记得你跟阿龙小时候无父无母
Don't you remember when you were a young kid living on the streets?
在街边跟狗抢东西吃
You and Lung, living among the filth and the rats
你一身肮脏衣服 破破烂烂
without any clothes, with nothing to eat!
谁把你们带回来的
And who was it that took you in?
这十几年来我辛辛苦苦把你们养大
For 10 years l struggled to give you an education,
像我亲儿子 还供你们念书
to bring you up like my own sons
我有没有收过你们一个钱
l asked for nothing in return
你为什么要贪钱给别人舞狮
And this is how you repay me?
你为什么要这样做
Why did you do it?
阿龙又不长进
Lung is a mediocre student
我这个武馆全靠你了
You're the one we depend on!
你这样做是不是要气死我
l don't understand how you could do it!
都说他不可靠
l don't believe it, he's betrayed us!
师父早晚给气死了
How could he do this to the master?
你说 你说
Talk!
不用说了
No, please!
你对我好 我对不起你 我走
You were good to me, l know l did wrong! l'm leaving!
大师兄
Brother..
别拦着我
Out of my way!
师父
Master!
大师兄
Brother!
让他去
Leave him!
你只管走 以后不要回来
And don't you ever come back here you hear me?
大师兄
Brother!...Brother!
听说大哥过两天就解上省府提审
l've heard that Master Kim's gonna be put on trial in a couple of days
再不动手恐怕就没有机会了
lf we don't do something they're gonna send him to prison
那么容易 你们才两个人
What're you gonna do? Go and rescue him?
人手是否太单薄了一点
You won't get far with just 2 of you
就我们两个还不够吗
l'd say the two of us should be plenty
那些公差只知道要钱
All those guards are overweight
也没有练功
They never practise kung fu
说打呀 决不是我们的对手
No sweat. They won't be a match for us!
那金少爷怎么会让人抓住
ln that case how come Kim was caught?
那天他喝醉了才会那么倒霉
He'd had a little too much to drink that day
不然十个五省捕头也对付不了他
Otherwise it'd have taken 10 of them
话不是这么说 凡事要从长计议
Maybe so. Still you'll have to plan it very carefully
舅舅 那么早就起来
Morning! Uncle, you're up early
喝茶了没有
Would you like some hot tea?
喝茶 还没有
Not yet
一块儿去吧
Let's go together
是你呀 想来学功夫呀
lt's you. What do you want? You here for lessons?
我是来找舅舅的
l come to see Uncle
找舅舅 舅舅 找您的
Uncle! A visitor
你来这儿干什么
Well? What are you doing here?
上次舞狮的钱我不是已经给你吗
Don't tell me you want money l already paid you, didn't l?
你想预支点明年的钱
Tell me what you want
不是 上次你不是说有个
No, it's not the money
教头的空位留给我的吗
it's the instructor's job you offered me
那是上个月的事
But that was last month
现在我又多了两个师兄
l've more instructors than l need right now
如果你那家武馆人手不够
Maybe if your school is short handed at the moment
我还想请你关照关照我的人呢
l could hire them to you
原来你是骗我
But you gave your word!
舅舅 早
Morning, Uncle!
你像什么 扣子也不扣好
Look at the state of you. Fasten those buttons
舅舅 他来干什么
Uncle, why's he here?
他想我们收留他
He wants us to employ him
你以为大米便宜呀
As if rice grew on trees!
上次你帮我们舞狮
When you performed the lion dance
事先我也不知道
l didn't know about all this
后来我也过意不去
l felt bad afterwards
如果我再收留你
Look, if we do take you in here
怕你师父会误会更深
your master will get even madder
我想他也是为了这件事赶你出来的
He found out and kicked you out, didn't he?
不如我跟你师父说几句好话 求求情
Maybe l can put in a good word for you
让你再回去吧
Maybe then he'll take you back
不用了
Forget it
天下那么大 我不信没地方去
The world is big, l'll find another place
等一等
Wait up there!
怎么 又有什么好关照
Well? What is it you want now?
我这次关照你走条财路
l've an offer that you might find interesting
就看你敢不敢做
and which could make you rich
现在我还有什么路可走 说吧
Beggars can't be choosers, l guess. Go ahead
师父 里面没有位子了
lt's full inside
先坐一下吧
Please wait
让开一点
Out of the way!
田师父 这么早 等位置呀
Master Tien. Oh, dear! You're still waiting for a table?
阿标 给你留了位了
Master, your table's ready
你们慢慢等吧
Won't be long. Yes, l'm coming!
舅舅
Uncle
那边有位子
There's a table
田师父 早
Master Tien, good morning
跟徒弟一块儿来喝茶
Having breakfast with your student?
对不起
Please excuse me
伙计 结帐
Waiter, check please!
来 有位子了
- Coming! - There's a table
走喇 对呀
- You're leaving, sir? - Yes
三块六
Check, $3.6!
谢谢谢谢
Thank you...Thank you
阿标 说起昨天你舞那狮子头真棒
Say, l must say that lion dance of yours was great
实在了不起 太好了
l've not seen anything like it!
我不是吹牛
What did l tell you? l wasn't lying
所以我舞狮你一定要看
When l promise l deliver the goods
是我们大师兄帮你的
lt was our big brother who helped you!
连饭都没得吃
Your school's so pitiful
招牌要是有脚也走啦
Your banner would run away if it could
你看我们顿顿大鱼大肉
Look at us here.
赶他们 他们也不肯走呀
We're fit and healthy fellas!
你看看你
Whereas look at your pathetic students!
瘦得皮包骨头像个猴
They're all bags of skin and bone. You're wasting away!
等我做做好事 请你吃个肉包子
Why don't you have a nice pork bun on me?
看他这个样子就是饿坏了
The poor boy must be starving to death
你胆子倒不小
You're pretty brave, sonny!
揍他
Beat him up!
穿抛挂哨插插插
Straight, upper cut, right hook,
看看我的挂锤
left hook, jab...
阿标 别玩了 你看师父生气啦
Wait! Calm down. Don't do that You see you've annoyed Master Tien
人家好歹也是个师父呀
He's a grand master, he deserves your respect
走
Come on!
师父 你还没给钱啦
But Master, you haven't paid yet!
我们没吃东西
We didn't eat anything
喝茶也得给钱呀
What about the cover charge?
谢谢师父 谢谢
Thank you master, thank you
师父 师父
Master..
怎么这么快就喝完茶啦
What's up with master?
你怎么弄成这个样子
What happened to your eye?
都是他
All this is his fault
舞狮子已经输了给人家
The stupid idiot lost the lion contest
还害得我让人家打成这样
Now everybody thinks they can beat us up!
是谁呀
Who did it?
功夫不够人打 就真羞死
Tell me little birdie with your spindly legs
how can you hope to take us down a peg?
我们过去给他们见识一下
Let's show them some real kung fu!
我不过去了
l don't think so
那你还不去
Go on, show them!
一块过去
Let's go get them!
回来
Stop!
你们还没有把脸丢够 回去
Haven't you all been shamed enough? Let's go!
你们怎么跟木头似的站在这儿干嘛
Don't just stand there, you heard the master!
师父叫回去 快回去 走
Let's go! Get a move on!
走啦 师弟
Come on!
功夫没学好 尽在外面惹事生非
You want to cause trouble, but you've no idea at all how to fight
我什么脸都给你们丢尽
You've humiliated me once again!
是他们先惹我们的
But it was the others, they started it
如果大师兄在 那我们就
Without Big Brother, we couldn't...
多嘴 整天大师兄大师兄的
Be quiet! All you know is 'Big Brother'!
难道我只教大师兄 没教你们吗
l taught all you boys kung fu
你刚才打的是什么拳
What kind of fighting did you call that?
再打给我看看 来
Show me again!
打
Go on!...
穿抛
Jab...Hook
抛 还有什么
Hook? And the rest?
挂
Throw
挂挂我这样教你吗 还有什么
Throw? Throw? Did l teach you that? Well, did l?
插 插
Jab, jab
插 插你的头
Useless! l've never seen anything so pitiful!
还有什么
Go on! The rest!
包 包 包
Hide!
包你的皮 你这个臭小子
Hide? That's all you're good for!
没用的东西
You're a disgrace! You're useless, pathetic! Good for nothing! ldiot!
我做了你们的师父
Do you know what it's like to be your master?
真是倒八辈子的霉
lt's a nightmare!
你们没一个是好东西
You're all as useless as each other!
不是窝囊废就是吃里扒外
You can't even fight and you're disloyal!
为了几个臭钱去替别人舞狮
Performing the lion dance for our competitors
用我教你们的功夫来拆我的台
lt's as if you'd used the kung fu l taught you against me!
弄得我们正风武馆
And what about our reputation?
现在什么名誉都没有了
We've been made a laughing stock!
连喝口茶都要受人家的气
They were laughing at me at the tea house
你们还有什么丢脸的事没有做
You've ruined 25 years of work!
还哭
Shut up!
你看看你 你功夫怎么练的
And you! Look at the state of you
胖得像个猪一样
You couldn't fight to save your life!
还有你 最小是你
And you too! Always hiding away!
最顽皮也是你 没打你你就哭
Always whimpering too!
你哭什么
l haven't touched you, what's the matter?
你看你 师父
- Look at yourself - Master, l...
你的腰带怎么绑的 你说 你说
What do you call this?
我教你这样绑的吗 你说 你说
Did l teach you to tie your belt this way? Tell me!
真是气死我了
You really piss me off!
你还要哭 不许哭 师父
- Are you still crying? Just stop it! - Master! Master!
师父 你为什么要怪我们呢
lt's not fair blaming us for this!
都是那野孩子不好
lt's those orphan boy's fault!
他吃里扒外
He sold us out!
关我们什么事
Why don't you punish him?
不许吵
Be quiet!
还在顶嘴 顶嘴 顶嘴
Don't you dare answer me back!
够了
That's enough!
为了那个金狮
Because we lost the contest
你赶走了大师兄
you chased away Brother Jing
现在又打他们出气
Now you're taking it out on us
你把自已的徒弟当成什么呢
What have we done to deserve it?
不错 我和大师兄是孤儿
lt's true, the two of us are orphan boys
吃你的 住你的
You house us, feed us
又没有缴学费 还这么没出息
We don't pay the fees here
你要打就打我吧
lf we've let you down then go ahead, beat me!
我的肉厚一点
Don't take it out on the rest
我知道师父你最恨我
You see you dislike me the most
连打我也省了
You won't even hit me
要是今天你不打我
But you'll only have one chance
以后就没有机会了
l won't give you another one
我知道要不是师父你收留我们
l admit if you hadn't taken us in back then
我跟大师兄早就饿死了
Brother Jing and l would be dead by now
我就不会丢你的脸
And this wouldn't have happened
大师兄也不会去帮人家舞狮
Jing wouldn't have betrayed you master
更不会被人看不起
and the others wouldn't all hate us
管我们叫野孩子
because we were orphans
我现在明白大师兄为什么要走
But maybe it was better for Brother Jing to leave the school
一个人怎么能够在一个没有人
Because it saved him from being humiliated
看得起的地方生活下去呢
like this in front of everyone!
师父 大师兄走得太匆忙
Master, Brother Jing's not here anymore
没时间跟你说
so l'll speak for him, too
我现在替他跟你说了吧
l know he'd agree with what l'm going to say
多谢师父你二十几年来的栽培
Thank you for having raised us like your own sons for all these years
我走啦
l'll go now
到那儿去
Hold it!
如果大师兄没有饿死的话
lf Brother Jing is still alive
我也会有地方去的
we'll find a place to go
站住
Stay there!
好 你走
Go if you want to
回来的时候把大师兄带回来
But bring your brother back with you
我们威义堂何时成了难民收容所
This school's becoming more of a refugee camp every day
会有那么多难民来投靠
How many more are we going to take in?
用不着这样嘛
What's your problem?
大家都是吃武馆饭的
l haven't asked you for anything, have l?
我们威义堂顿顿大鱼大肉
We're the best school, they're hammering on the door to get in!
你们呢 一块腐乳还得吃三顿
You pal, you're not up to our standard
什么叫吃武馆饭的 谁认识你
What right do you have to be here? You're a nobody!
标哥 别叫得那么好听
- Brother, l.. - Did l say we were brothers?
我今天来的目的是
Look, l just came here to...
别说了
That's enough!
好不容易就要带那两家伙走啦
l just got rid of one competitor
现在我说了算啦
l'm top dog here
别在这儿碍手碍脚的
l don't want you walking on my toes!
我只不过 走
- Look, l only... - Get lost!
野孩子 快滚
Go to hell, orphan boy!
用不着出口伤人嘛
l don't like people calling me that
出口伤人
And l don't care what you like
你再不走我还要出手打人
Maybe l should explain it to you
阿标 你没事吧
Brother! Are you hurt?
没事
No, l'm alright
这么大个子站都站不稳
You're not very stable for a fat man, are you?
一定是你师父叫你扎马的时候
l bet you used to play hooky instead of
跑去睡懒觉的嘛
practising your kung fu
去叫馆主
Get the owner!
你真的没事
Sure you're alright?
没事没事 你就说有人来踢馆
Of course, don't worry. Tell him we got trouble!
躺下
Good night!
这么胖起不了来吧
Fatty, l thought you'd bounce back up!
别打 别打 别打他了
Stop it! Stop fighting!
算你运气好
l'll let you off this time!
阿标 别再打他了
Brother, stop it. No more fighting!
一直都是他在打我
He's the one beating me up, master
你叫他不要打我才对
Tell him to stop fighting!
你到这儿来是
What do you want here?
我来是看看我大师兄来过了没有
No sir, l'm here looking for Brother Jing
他来过 他还让我收留他
He came here looking for ajob
可是我没有这样做
But l couldn't take him
我还以为你来这儿抢我饭碗呢
l thought you were looking for trouble, and that you wanted my job!
馆主 打搅了
Well, too bad. Thanks a lot
标哥 对不起呀
Brother, l'm sorry
好了 没事啦 回去吧
Alright, that's enough. Back to work
停
Halt!
休息一会吧
Here, drink some water. Come on, guys!
起程
Let's go!
来了
Look, they're here!
停
Halt!
上
Weapons!
我要他
Let him go!
上
Get him!
大哥
Master! Great to see you!
大哥 你好吗
Master, are you alright?
他是谁
Who's he?
大哥 他是自已人呀
He's with us, master
走
Let's go!
快点回去报告 说囚车被人劫了
Go quickly! Tell them he escaped!
说被什么人劫了
Who shall l say attacked us?
那个拿白扇子劫的
A man with a white fan
多谢
Thanks.
随便看看
Take a look, sir
朋友 你见过拿这样扇子的人吗
Tell me, have you seen a man carrying a white fan like this?
拿钱来买东西的人就见过
l don't have time to look at people unless they have money
刚开市你就来搅惑 快给我滚 滚
Now stop wasting my time. Move!
还不走
Hurry up!
随便看看
Good morning, sir!
那不是拿白扇子的吗
lt's the man with the white fan!
我看不像
l don't think so
看清楚点
l'm sure he's the one
像不像啊
There! You see that?
还是不像
lt doesn't look like him
所以说 官府画的图 何时画得像贼
You know these sketches are never accurate
有花红呀
There's a big reward, you know
有花红
A reward?
这单生意可以做
ln that case it's definitely the one!
你去叫兄弟们来
You get reinforcements, right?
我去跟着他 快点
And l'll follow him. Hurry up!
他在里面 你们跟着来
He's in the temple. Follow me!
怎么不见了 是呀
- What the...? - Where did he go?
明明在这儿拜神的嘛 到那儿去了
He was in front of the altar. Where'd he go?
阿弥陀佛
Buddha bless you
你们是来找我的吗
Can l help you gentlemen?
五位公差大人 有什么不对吗
Five constables all together. There must be a problem
白扇子 你死到临头还要多嘴
Mr white fan, the game's up
快点跟我回去
You're coming back with me. You're under arrest!
别急公差大人 我没有犯法
l've done nothing wrong!
你们找错人了吧
You made a mistake, you have the wrong man
我的眼睛还会看错
l never make any mistake
难道劫囚车的那个人是你兄弟
Unless the fugitive we're chasing after is your double!
给我锁
Lock him up!
上呀
Get him!
把刀给我
Give me your sword!
你没事吧
You alright?
没事 把刀给我
l'm alright. Give me a sword!
谢谢
Thank you.
连菩萨的脑袋你都敢砍
You chopped off Buddha's head!
对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry... Out of the way!
我们是不信神的
You don't fool me! l don't believe in god!
砍他
Get him!
反正你不信神 我就一刀送你上天堂
l guess if you don't believe in god you won't be going to heaven!
害怕啦 只是砍到你的手铐
You were lucky. You were saved by your handcuffs!
对啊
Really?
以前是不信 现在信极了
l think l changed my mind. l do believe in god now
信了 还不快去还神
lf you believe you better go pray
把刀给我
Give me your sword!
你还过来
Still want to fight?
十字架你怕不怕
Aren't you afraid of the cross?
你没事吧
Brother, are you alright?
没事 上
Of course l am, get him!
你想走呀
Brother, are you leaving?
不是 拿刀给我
No way, give me a sword!
都让你拿光了
We don't have any swords left!
这下可糟啦 你先盯住
Things don't look good. You stay here,
我去找三公
l'll find Sam Kung
你那么辛苦 还是我去
Wait a minute! l'll find Sam Kung, it's no trouble
你去衙门 我去三公家
Wait a minute! You find him, l'll help you
三公 开门呀 三公 开门呀
Sam Kung! Open up! Sam Kung! Open up!
四哥 三公在不在家
Hello, is Sam Kung here?
四哥
Hey, brother! Hey!
你怎么了 叫你那么多声都不理人家
What's the matter? Have you gone deaf? Why don't you answer him?
斗鸡眼 什么事
What's the matter? What do you want?
秀姐 今天我跟一班兄弟
Sister, my colleagues and l, we caught the man
在破庙里抓到白扇子了
the man with the white fan!
你抓到了白扇子
You caught the man with the white fan?
是呀 所以我现在
That's right. So l came for Sam Kung
请三公去跟他录口供呀
So he can interrogate the man
我爸爸今天一早到衙门捕房去了
My father left for the police post early this morning
三公不在呀那怎么办
You mean he's not here?
谁去给他去录口供呀
ln that case who's going to interrogate him?
录口供是吧
You don't need him for that
既然你已经把他抓到了
lf you really have him prisoner,
送到衙门不就得啦
you can interrogate him yourselves
可是我请不动他呀
We haven't quite caught him yet
我来帮你去请他吧
l suppose you'll be needing help again!
你到那儿去呀 又想去打架
Where are you going? Picking fights again?
人家戏都散场了 你去干什么
They didn't say anything about needing help!
我去了跟着演续集 走吧
l'm only doing my civic duty. Let's go!
小心让爸爸知道
lf father finds out...!
你不说他怎么会知道
lf he does l'll know who told him!
四哥 那个人就在那边
Brother! That's the man there!
去呀
Go on then!
他见了我就不高兴 还是你去吧
Yes but we don't see eye to eye. Would you go for me?
对不起
Excuse me
你这个人怎么犯蹩扭 让你先走
Look l don't want trouble so you just go ahead
你想抢我东西
Are you trying to steal my money?
别欺负我是外地来的呀
l'm not an easy target you know!
好小子 给点厉害你瞧瞧
Alright let's see how good you are!
想抢我的东西
You're gonna have to do better
可没那么容易
l told you it wouldn't be easy!
你到底是什么人
Who the hell are you?
没空跟你玩
l don't have time for this
四哥 想不到你的马步扎得那么好
Brother, you were really great! That stance of yours, legs part
手够劲 马四平 双眼似铜铃
with perfect balance, eyes on your opponent
这两百块花红咱们拿定了
Just keep it up, the reward is ours!
人呢
Where is he?
我看见他从那边走了
l think he went that way
你怎么不早说
Keep your eyes open!
老伯 我喝杯茶行吗
Old man, may l have some tea please?
行 不用客气
Sure
谢谢
Thank you
坐
Sit down
谢谢
Thank you
看你这一身的汗
How come you're in such a sweat?
别提了 今天我倒了八辈子的霉
To be honest, this has been a pretty terrible day for me
不知道从什么地方钻出来一条哑吧狗
l was walking peacefully along the way
一句话没说就跟我打起来了
just now and some maniac attacked me
还有几个衙门里的混蛋想打我一顿
And earlier on this morning l was set upon by some policemen
幸亏我跑得快
Luckily l managed to escape
要不然我也不会坐在这儿喝茶了
Otherwise l wouldn't be here now drinking tea with you
老伯 你的烟杆好漂亮 看看行吗
That's a really neat pipe you have here. Can l take a look?
行 随便看吧
Sure. Take a look, no problem
看清楚点 以后没机会再看啦
Take a good look. You won't get another chance to see it
御赐
The royal seal?
可不是鱼翅呀
And it's not a forgery either
是古董呢
Must be worth a fortune!
兄弟 你这把扇子好大
That's a big fan you have there
我倒想见识见识
Would you mind if l took a look at it, sir?
老伯 你可真有眼光
Old man, you have an eye for quality
有名堂的
You see it's inscribed
金龙白纸扇
The golden dragon white scroll fan
不错吧
Nice fan?
没错
lt's beautiful!
说起这把扇子可不简单
lt's had its glory days l don't mind telling you
不过跟你说了也没什么用
l don't suppose you're interested
再喝一杯茶
Why don't you have some more tea?
老伯 你对人真客气 又健谈
You know you're a very hospitable person
你是住在这里吗
So do you live here?
不是 我是在这儿等人的
No. l'm just waiting for somebody
说起这个人可真是不简单
The person l'm waiting for is someone exceptional
怎么样不简单
ln what way?
他劫囚车 还抢钱庄
He ambushed a prison convoy and robbed a money lender
连官府通缉他都不当一回事
He could be face to face with the police chief
就算是五省捕头 他也不当一回事
and not be afraid
这个人那么厉害
This man must really be something!
不过 他是个近视眼
Except that he's very short sighted
近视眼
Really?
不是什么都看不清楚了吗
You mean like he could bump into you? He'd never even see you
他就跟瞎了一样 他已经来啦
And he's right there!
来了 没有呀
He's here?
你看不见而已
You can't see him?
是他呀
That's the man?
我说那个哑吧狗就是这小子
He's the maniac l told you about who attacked me!
他也咬过您呀
Did he give you trouble?
他岂止咬我 住我的吃我的
No, he didn't give me any trouble. He just eats and sleeps with me
还吼着我
keeps an eye on things
吼着你什么
An eye on what?
我的家产
My money and gold
你也太缺德了 连老头儿你也欺负
l know what your game is now, bullying old people!
我第一眼看你就觉得你不是个好人
From the moment l set eyes on you l was sure you were up to no good!
现在被官府通缉啦
So you're a wanted man?
说得你多么了不起 你叫什么名字
l hear that you're quite a legend. So what's your name?
真哑吧
Not talking?
我老听人家说
What's up? Has the cat got your tongue?
缺德的人要是生儿子没屁眼的
Or maybe it's some kind of birth defect?
他爹生他这个儿子一定是没舌头的
Maybe his father was such a big mouth that his son was born a mute!
你还笑
You be quiet!
你先别生气 让我来收拾他
No! Stay out of this! l'll take care of this guy
板凳仔 你这个小王八蛋
Alright, funny guy!
这回我可不放过你
This time it'll be different. l'm not gonna let you off so easily!
这小子也会耍板凳
l must say my son's good with that bench
好小子 有两下子
Not bad! But watch this!
对付这小子
lf you really want to beat this rascal
把这个拿去
you'll need a pole
多谢老伯
Thanks, old man
这回完了吧
Had enough?
老伯 您借我的这根东西真好用
Old man, the pole really worked well. l can't thank you enough
当然 你不靠我这根东西怎能收拾他
lt was obvious there was no way to beat him without using the pole
你现在动也不能动了吧
That's for sure. You can't move now, can you?
老伯 这一巴掌是我替你打的
Old man, just for you, l'll teach him a little lesson
这一巴掌呢是我打你的
And this lesson comes from yours truly here
还有这一巴掌呢
And this lesson here comes from
是我替你死鬼老头打的
your big mouth of a father
这
And this...
老伯 他还瞪你呢
See that? He's making faces!
你先站到一旁
Stand back a moment
好啊 轮到您打
Sure. Your turn to beat him
叫你别出来到处乱跑
l told you not to go out looking for trouble
你当我是耳边风
but you never listen, do you?
叫你姐姐看着你 你又不练功
l tell you to practise your kung fu but you're just too lazy!
以为自已板凳耍得好 就到处显威风
Just because your bench work is above average you think you can cause trouble?
现在让人家打得你舒服了吧
Well, now somebody's given you a good beating!
老伯 你怎么知道他那么详细
Old man, how do you know all this?
他是我的种
We're like peas in a pod
你的种
You're like what?
他是我的根
Tree and sapling
你的根
l don't get it
就是我儿子
l'm the boy's father!
那你不就是他爹
You're his old man, l see!
算起来也有点便宜
l still won the fight!
起来呀你
Come on, get up!
原来你父子俩是一伙的
lt's 2 onto 1 now, l should've guessed!
你这个老家伙戏演得真不错
That was pretty good acting l must say
你这个臭小子真该死
At last we get to the bit where you die
我等了你一整天 连饭也还没吃
l had to wait all day without eating for you to turn up
你等一会 没吃饭是吧 早点说嘛
This is all about food! Why didn't you say so?
这个容易 大票我就没有
lt's no problem. l don't have much cash
零钱还有一点儿
But why don't you take this?
你们两个吃饭也足够啦
lt's enough to buy dinner for both of you
有饭吃还打人
l just offered to buy you dinner!
跪下
Kneel down
用不着你请客
You can keep your money
我爹吃了几十年公家饭了
We get our meals paid courtesy of the emperor!
你爹是当差呀
You mean he's a policeman?
那还用说
Chief of police!
你跑出来干什么
What are you doing out of the house?
姐姐叫我出来买鱼虫
Sister told me to do the shopping
还不快去
Go do it!
你最好少多嘴
You have the right to remain silent
你所讲的话将会作呈堂证供
But anything you do say may be taken down and used as evidence in court
你一定听很多遍
l've heard that somewhere
拿着扇子 你还不承认
before you were carrying a fan
媒婆也拿着扇子 你怎么不去抓她
So do matchmakers, why don't you arrest all of them too?
你儿子也好不到那儿去
And your son while you're at it
不声不响到处乱逛
He's a menace with that stupid bench of his!
不要再提起他了好吗
Don't mention that wastrel!
他一定不是你的亲生儿子
l doubt whether he's your real son
要不然他怎会不听你的话
Otherwise why'd he behave like that?
一提起他我就有气
l get mad just looking at him
一天到晚闷声不响
He never says a word
屁都不多放一个 简直像个哑吧
l don't want to talk about it!
你们父子俩也没话说
You don't talk to each other?
可不是嘛
Hardly a word.
那有咱们两个这么聊得来
Makes a change having you here
那倒也是
Yeah, right!
走吧
Move it!
小个便行吗
Wait! l need to take a leak!
小便 到前面
Take a leak? Come on!
你锁住我 我怎么尿呀
l can't do it with the handcuffs on!
把东西放下 我放开你不就行了
l'll take them off but not for long
老伯 说实在的你真是个好人
Old man, you're not a bad person
你看着我 我怎么尿
l can't do it with you watching!
不看着你 你跑了怎么办
But if l don't watch you you'll be off down the trail!
这样你看着我也要跑
l might just run anyway!
我走
Here l go, l'm running away!
你怎么不追我 我真的走啦
He's nuts. Alright, l'm gone!
走 走 走 走得快好世界 走
l'm going, l'm running!
指那边走那边 真听话
As l thought, l point the way and off he goes!
他真的没有追来
He didn't follow me!
行了
Free at last!
怎么会变成这样的
What is this? l'm going down!
软绵绵的 这是怎么搞的
l'm sinking!
这个就叫贼人厕所
This place is called ''The Thieves' Toilet''
快点救我上来
Don't leave me here!
千万别呼气 不然会沉得更加快
The more you struggle, the further you'll sink in
你快救我上来
Please help me out of here!
凡是犯人到了这儿
You got yourself into this mess
个个都会自动走下去的
So get yourself out without my help
老伯 你快救救我
But l could drown in here!
怕什么 还没有盖过头呢
As long as your head's above water, it's okay
救你上来也行
l tell you what
你要先唱个歌给我听
l'll get you out if you sing me a song
唱得好听呢 我就考虑你的请求
But you better sing good
我唱
Alright
有只小鸟掉下水 掉下水 掉下水
London Bridge is falling down...
有
Falling...
怎么不唱下去
Don't stop, you were doing good!
捉住竹枝 再沉的话 便很难救
lf you sink any further it'll be too late!
抓住 抓住
Go on! Hold on tight!
上来
That's it! Come on!
慢慢来
You're almost there.
快行了
That's right
差点淹死
l nearly drowned
走开走开 别把东西弄脏了
Don't stand there, you're making everything dirty
救我
Help me!
快点救我上来
Get me out of here!
你这个人倒挺好心的
You're a good person too
其实你可以趁机跑掉
You could have run away and left me
对呀
You're right!
幸亏你提醒我
Thanks for reminding me of that!
谢谢你 我走啦
l'm getting out of here! Goodbye!
快点 最多我唱只歌给你听
You can't just leave me here! l'll sing you a song!
救救我
What'd you say?
你唱吧
Alright, sing!
有只小鸟掉下水 掉
London Bridge is falling down...
别唱了别唱了 你唱得好肉麻
Forget it! Don't bother it's terrible!
我救你上来吧
l'll get you out!
快点
Hurry!
抓紧 断了是你的不幸
Catch this! Hold on tight! lf it breaks it's your fault!
有人在吗 有人在吗
Anyone home? Open the door!
怎么那么倒霉
Talk about unlucky
姑娘 姑娘
Miss! Over here!
你是谁呀
Who are you?
我就是我
Me? l'm just me
你能不能把门开一开呀
Can you open the door, please?
行了 我笑着回答讲一声我是我
lt worked. Me, l'm just me
姑娘 姑娘
Hello, Hello
我替你擦干净 对不起
l'll clean it off, sorry
行了行了 你从哪儿来的
No, forget it. You from round here?
不是 我是从泥潭来的
Not really. But this mud is
我是说你从外地来的
l thought not, it was pretty obvious
要不然怎么会掉在泥潭里
The locals don't fall in the swamp
可不是 你看我的狼狈相
l guess not. l must look terrible
一身都是泥
l apologize, Miss
我进去拿桶水冲一冲就行了
l'll look better if you'd allow me to wash up
我不会弄脏你的地的
l won't make any mess
姑娘 你把那个东西借给我用行吗
Excuse me, can l borrow that thing there?
拿去
Here
谢谢
Thank you
厉害罢
lt takes practice
是我带你去洗澡还是你带我去洗澡
This is my house, l didn't tell you to go inside, did l?
这法子倒挺好
Right, you can come in
当然好了 没有了脚印
Thank goodness for that. No dirty footprints
追我的就不太好了
At least he won't follow me in here
行了行了 就在这儿下来吧
lt's alright. You can walk from now on
谢谢 那儿是洗澡房
- Thank you - The bathroom's down there.
你自已进去吧
Just make yourself at home
谢谢
Thanks a lot!
这是男女不分的
Men and women together?
你衣服这么脏 怎么能穿呢
You can't put those dirty things back on
我去拿我弟弟衣服给你换
l'll get you some of my brother's clothes
衣服挂在这里
l'll leave them out here
谢谢
Thank you
糟了 忘了买菜
Oh, no. l forgot the shopping
我要赶着出去买菜
l have to go to the market
你自已在这儿洗可以了吧
you'll be alright by yourself, won't you?
行了 你去吧 我自已洗没问题
Sure, no problem. You go right ahead
没问题 没问题
l'll be fine. l'll be fine
不管多脏都没问题
l've got no worries, l'll be fine!
想起了五省捕头可就大问题
The police chief? Oh who cares!
岂有此理
Just you wait!
下次再让我看到那个臭小子
lf l set eyes on that good for nothing again
我就一刀劈死他 免得跟他噜苏
l won't even say a word to him
还好他们两个没回来
Good, there's no one home
这小子这么快就回来
That good for nothing son's here
她弟弟
Her brother?
怎么那么脏
How come it's so dirty?
没摔着吧 我是跟你开玩笑啦
l'm sorry, fish. l was only playing around, really!
人工呼吸都不行
Mouth to mouth isn't working!
你这臭小子 鱼都快被你弄死
Stupid idiot! Now you've killed the goldfish!
原来是你 真巧
- What? You here? - lt's a mistake!
这次我看你往那儿跑
You won't escape me this time!
你这个人可真不讲理
You're a real pain in the rear?
我跟你都是借人家地方用嘛
We could've shared like civilized human beings
你看你把这个地方弄得肮肮脏脏的
But you messed everything up!
还躲起来要我帮你
So l had to clean up after you
就算我是借
Now listen you!
我说过了
l said when l saw you
让我再见到你我决不跟你噜苏
that not one word would pass between us!
那更好 我们大家耳根都清静
Suits me fine. l don't want to talk to you in any case
不关你的事
Not you, fishy
它肚子反啦
lt's dead!
我替你开刀
Come back here you!
你不要滥用私刑
There are laws in this country!
我宰了你 就报你个失踪
l'll kill you and report you're missing
你那把刀可真快呀
You're pretty fast with your sword
原来是御赐
The pipe with the royal seal!
虽然是御赐的
This pipe is pretty well made
为什么又会刀枪不入呢
l guess you could use it as a weapon
御赐砍御赐 御赐胡乱刺 刺
Royal seal...Royal seal...
我敲
Knock it
敲头敲不破
lt doesn't break against bone
不知敲柱破不破
l wonder what it's like against wood
还是不破 我再敲
lt still didn't break!
怎么还是不破
Not a scratch!
先把烟杆放下来
Put the pipe down right away!
那你先把刀放下
First you put down the sword!
你先放下烟杆
You put the pipe down first
好 我先把刀放下
Alright, l'll put the sword down
这还差不多
That's more like it
我只是把刀插回去
l'm just putting it back in the scabbard
你 不是我 是他
- What's this? - l'm sorry but it's him!
这些家俱都是他打坏的
He started breaking the furniture
是他 是他 你打他呀 打他
lt's his fault. Beat him up! Go on!
你快打他呀
What're you waiting for?
爸爸
Father!
又是你爸爸 你可真有福气
He's your father? What's wrong with you?
满街都是你儿女
You've got children everywhere!
够了吧
That's enough!
我扫
Right!
算我倒霉
Now l'm really mad!
我可是让你的呀
l'll let you win this once!
玩完了没有呀
Have you finished playing?
玩完了
Yes, l've finished
好了 就在这儿休息一会吧
Alright, we'll rest here
这儿是条死路
You mean here? A dead end?
无遮无盖 有什么好
There isn't any shelter. Forget it!
好就好在是死路
A dead end is easier to defend
三公 我好急呀
Mister Kung, l really need to pee
听见了没有 又要撒尿了 请便
Right, he needs to pee. Go ahead
除非你撒尿射塌了墙
Unless you can break down a brick wall with your pee
再想借尿遁可别要指望了
there's no way of escaping
不是呀 我这次是真的
l promise, l'm not making it up
好 把他解开
Son, release him
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢四哥
Thank you, brother
你别看着我 要不然我尿得不痛快
Please don't watch me, otherwise l can't pee
干什么
What're you doing?
没什么 我习惯了这样撒尿
lt's just a bad habit of mine
手力很好 干什么 练功呀
Practising your kung fu?
不是 我在量这条巷有多宽
No l was just measuring the width of the alley
量完了吧 还不下去
Now you know. Back you go!
吃吧
Want some?
四哥 你爹在我面前把你臭得
Tell me this, why does your dad always belittle you in front of me
一无是处 我真替你不值
l almost feel sorry for you
真难为你想出这样的法子来锁我
What are all the bells and the chains for?
你一定是以为我随时都会逃跑吧
Don't tell me you really expect me to escape?
你想跑就摇摇个铃铛
lf you do escape you'll be easy to find
好让我有个准备
l'll just follow the ringing
白日依山尽 黄河入海流
The grand old duke of York, he had 10 thousand men
欲穷千里目 更上一层楼
He marched them up to the top of the hill and...
楼上没什么看 请你快下楼
How does the rest of it go?
成个跟屁虫 生他气 他又不知
l don't believe this, he's sticking to me
骂他又不好意思
closer than my own shadow!
五省捕快 五省捕快
Wait up, Chief Sam Kung!
我找得你好苦呀
You're such a hard man to find
是你呀 是我
- lt's you - Yes, is me.
找我有什么事
What do you want?
我刚刚经过路边社
l was in the market today and l overheard two men talking about...
我听说不知道什么人抢什么
lt's gone right out of my head
抢抢劫钱庄
l remember what it was now
白扇子跟几个人
The man with the white fan
准备在午时抢劫万隆钱庄
is going to rob the Man Lung Bank at five o'clock!
白扇子
White Fan?
午时
At five o'clock?
你没有骗我吧
You're not telling me lies?
不会 这么久以来何时骗过你
No, have l ever lied to you before, chief?
刚才线人说白扇子去抢劫钱庄
My informerjust told me White Fan is planning a robbery
那我岂不是抓错人
So he is the wrong man?
你看 我早就说你们抓错人
l told you, didn't l? l'm not the bandit...
吵什么
Shut up!
真凶一天没有抓到你都是疑犯
As long as we haven't caught him, you're a suspect!
你再不放我 我就要告你们爷俩
lf you don't release me l'll sue you!
不告你 只告你这个老家伙
Not you. Just your dad
刚才你阻差办公 我就可以控告你
l could lock you up for obstructing justice!
你看着他 我去找人来
You watch him! l'll be back!
你这算什么 不讲理你这个人
How can you do this? lt's unfair!
我们合作一点 我不看着你
Tell you what
你也不要跑
l won't watch you if you don't run
那你把钥匙给我
So you'll give me the key?
等我回来再说
When l get back
我在这儿等你
Alright, but don't be too long
还不走 等神仙打救
He can't leave me!
怎么白扇子还不来
How come White Fan isn't here?
他们两个已经去了
All the others have left already
你怎么样呀
So where were you?
想打退堂鼓呀
Maybe he's afraid
怕什么 我才不怕
l've never been afraid in my whole life
那你现在还不去
You better go and join the others
不是说未时动身
l thought we weren't ready
还是早点好 反正也没订合同
Know what they say? No time like the present
好吧 我去了
Alright, l'm going
没有这小子碍手碍脚的
We'll get rid of that kid afterwards
咱们俩分得更多
then we can split his share
金爷 等这条借刀杀人之计
What we'll do is set him up
除掉这小子之后
so he takes the rap for the robbery
明天到伏处岭把赃物起出来
Then we can share out the loot at Tiger Peak
放我出来
Let me go, please
叫也没有用
Shut up, you fool!
我跟你分了它吧
Come on, let's go
弄出人命怎么办
What're we gonna do with him?
弄出人命有人负责
Maybe you should put his lights out
你的扇子在里面 去拿吧
Your fan's in there, don't forget it
你你什么意思
What do you think you're doing?
我告诉你
lf you want to know, the kick
这一脚是替金爷赐你的
in the pants was a present from brother Kim!
想跟我们一块平起平坐
lf you thought we'd give you a share
差得远啦
in the loot my friend, then you were mistaken
做我们的替死鬼吧
But we need a scapegoat!
就这么说 捡回扇子 牢里很热的
Don't forget your fan! Prisons are hot
看什么 看什么
- What's up? - What's up?
走开 有什么好看的
Get lost!
人看人有什么好看
Nothing to see here! Go on!
走开
Move it! Go on home!
我早就说过这儿有钱捡
l told you there'd be money for you all
你这个死老头 竟敢捉弄我
lf you're looking for trouble
最多我还给你
l'll give it back to you!
你打呀 你打 打呀
On my head! On my head!
手挺快的
He's pretty fast
打死我了 打死我了
Please stop it! You're hurting me!
哎呀这个老头就要给打死了
Look! They're gonna beat up that poor old man!
不要
No, please!...
死老头儿
Troublemaker!
不要踩死我了
No!...
你想要我的老命
Please don't trample on me...
我快死了
不要
No...
他的摊子散了
There goes your market stall!
我的布可不愁卖不出去了
Now l've got no more competition!
你没事吧
Are you alright?
走开
Move!
真会装蒜 不要
- Don't give me that! - No...
不要打了
Leave him alone!
走
Get off!
我死了
Take that!
胡子掉了
l see you lost your beard?
不可以跌
Can't fall
谢谢 多谢捧场
Thank you! Thank you for your support!
玩完
Game over.
还不死 没死
- Are you dead yet? - Not quite!
你究竟是谁
Who the hell are you?
拿去用吧
No, no! My shop!
我的布呀
My god!
别那么小器
Be generous
反正不是我的 拿去 统统拿去
Let away!
干什么呀你 要死啦你
What are you doing? Get out of there!
让我躲一下
Let me in
出来 出来
Get out of there!
死鬼 干什么呀你 真是色鬼
Stop it! Get out of there!
打得好痛
My ear really hurts!
不要脸 掀女人的裙子
Dirty old man, we'll call the police on you!
裙子
Skirts?
不可以跌
No...
我弹
l jump
又要马儿好 又要马儿不吃草
Time to go for a ride! Time to get off!
怎么老打一个地方
He keeps hitting my ear!
机灵点嘛
We better be careful!
那儿去了 在后面
Where is he? At the back
等我打断你的脚
We'll see how tough you are!
是他的 又打错啦
Didn't even hurt!
去死吧你
Go to hell
叫你机灵点 你还要来
lt's rude to peek in through windows!
别过去
No, stay out of it!
捡回钥匙
Where are those keys?
我的布 一会儿还给你
- What about my fabric? - You'll get it back!
官差来啦
Here's the police!
快走 官差来了
Let's go! Here's the police!
包围钱庄
Surround the door!
里面的人听着
Alright, you inside!
你们已经被你包围了
Come out, the place is surrounded!
我现在数三下
l'm gonna count to 3!
你们马上放下兵器出来投降
You'll come out quietly and put down your weapons!
一 二 三
One! Two! Three!
别动
Don't move!
我这个样子怎么能动呀
Come on, are you kidding?
大师兄 你别生气
Brother, don't be angry!
大师兄 我知道这样走很辛苦
Brother, l know it must be tough for you
顶多我陪你这样走
so l'll walk the same way, alright?
来 我答应过师父要带你回去见他的
l promised master l'd bring you home with me
如果你给人通缉 我怎样带你回去
l had to make sure you wouldn't run away again
所以你趁我不留意就把我锁住
You didn't have to tie me up like this!
我带你去和五省捕快谈判
l gotta take you to the police chief first
叫他不好再通缉你
he's the only one who can drop the charges!
混帐 你以为菜场买菜可以讲价的
Forget it! Do you think the law was made to be bargained away when it suits you?
法律不外乎人情
The law's meant to be compassionate!
国有国法 没得商量
lt's the same for everybody. No exceptions!
让人家将功赎罪也不行
But he repents what he did wrong
他劫囚车 做尽坏事 没有人情好讲
Attacking a police convoy can't be excused!
那你们公差有时候也会做坏事呀
But even government officials commit crimes
混帐 劫囚车是很大的罪名
Says who? At least we don't ambush convoys!
我把他捉回来不是等于没劫啦
lf l brought back the convict would it change things?
混帐
Ridiculous!
混帐 你就知道说混帐
What's ridiculous about it?
你砍了人一刀 人家伤好了
lf you cut somebody's arm the wound will heal
难道你说你没砍过
but you still cut his arm
好 现在我拿了你的烟杆
Alright. What if l take your pipe?
快放下我的烟杆
Put it down right now!
我现在放回去了不等于没拿吗
lf l put it back down then it's like l never took it
爹 反正上面追得这么急
Father, you don't have much time
他肯帮你捉 这不是很好吗
lf he wants to let him find Kim
捉人 难道我自已不会捉吗
Don't interfere. l can find Kim myself
你不知道他在那儿 我知道
You don't know where he is and l do
你不肯是吧
But if you don't want to do a deal
我和大师兄喝茶去不管啦
then it's your problem, mister
不许走
Wait a minute!
你窝藏通缉犯 连你一块抓
lf you're sheltering a fugitive, l'll have you arrested!
五省捕头 你不要迫人太甚
l wouldn't push too far if l were you!
话我可说到这儿 你自已考虑考虑
Here's the deal. l'll let you think it over
我敲三下就落锤成交
l'll count to 3 and bang on the table
肯不肯随你的便 一二三
and you give me your answer. Ready, 3!
好 好 好
Wait! Alright, alright!
那如果你抓不到金脚带回来
You'd better bring that criminal back with you
你就准备探监吧
or you'll be sharing his cell!
四六 五五 三七 你七我三
50! No, 40! Alright, 30!...
找人给你去做三七吧
Alright, you can take 70 percent!
金爷 我们朋友一场
lt's not in my nature to share things
给我留点纪念品总可以吧
For old times sake, leave me a small souvenir, won't you?
你想拿点去做纪念品是吗
You did say you wanted a souvenir
可以 拿去放骨头去吧
Alright, here. To bury your bones!
救命吧
No, please don't!
我接住了
lt's alright, l caught it!
是你呀
lt's you!
你可真毒辣 串谋金脚带害我大师兄
You really are a slimebag. You teamed up with him to trap my brother
你死一百次都应该
You're lucky l don't rip you apart!
那你为什么帮我接着这东西
Then why did you catch the pot?
我是怕埕了破了 伤害那些小孩
l don't like seeing nice things getting broken
臭小子碍手碍脚的
You're always in the way
你到这儿来干什么
So what are you doing here?
我 捉你回去交给五省捕头
l'm here to take you back to the police!
金脚带 捉蛇的来了
Serves you right. He's come to take you in
捉我 就凭你
You what? This squirt?
有什么好笑
What's so funny?
想想倒是挺好笑
lt's true, it does sound funny
亏你笑得出来
l don't hear you laughing!
你要小心点
You'd better be careful
这条金脚带很厉害的
He's an extremely dangerous fellow
尤其是他的虎尾脚
You better watch out for his Tiger Tail move
你这样的武功想捉我 作梦
Take me in? There's no chance!
完了 这小子要是打不过他
Damn! Whichever way this ends
我跟他一样的没命
the situation doesn't look good for me
我一定帮他打赢金脚带
l'd rather take my chances with the kid!
看着呀 中
Are you watching?
中上路 中下路
The legs! Legs head!
等会 我还没叫你你就冲出去了
Wait! Don't run back in there you'll get massacred!
他的下盘功夫很厉害
His leg skills are legendary, you don't have a chance
不如攻他的上三路
lnstead, you should attack his upper body
上三路
Upper body?
好呀
You're learning fast
真有你的 两三招下来
You've found out already
你就试探出他的上三路更厉害
that his upper body's even deadlier!
你怎么不早点说
Why didn't you tell me?
怕打终须打
lf you want to win a battle you have to take a few hits
多挨几下你就会习惯了嘛
You'll get used to it!
打的不是你 当然说得轻松呀
You can talk, you're not the one getting hit!
打到现在
Haven't you noticed something?
你还看不出他是单蹄马
Your opponent is a one legged horse
他只有左脚能使用
He always relies on his left leg!
你那么了解他 你去打好了
You're such an expert, you fight him!
我去了 谁替你做武术指导
lf l fight, there'll be no one to coach you
克难时期吃点苦 算不了什么
Pain means the muscle's working. You're doing just fine
不用怕 去
Go on!
起来 快 快起来
Come on, get up. What's the matter?
你为什么不还手
Go on, what're you doing?
我打不到他啊
l'm trying, you idiot!
现在不是打让赛
Stop playing and get stuck in!
别放手 就算是天塌下来也不要放手
Don't let go even if you're struck by lightning!
我打中他啦
Did you see that? l did it!
再接再励呀 你小心呀
Watch out! lt's not over! Behind you!
怎么会这么巧呀
l told you to be careful of him, didn't l?
这脚是踢得比较重
You walked right into that one, sonny!
他来了 他来了
Look out, here he comes!
快起来 快起来
Get up, kid, get up!
再接再励
Now get going, go on!
不要看了
l don't know to see
振作点 振作点
Don't give up, kid! Don't give up!
他再踢几脚就没气了
l know you can do it
没气脚就发软
Another couple of good kicks and he'll be on the ground
脚发软就轮到你发威啦
l know you can do it, kid!
我也没有气了
Stay with me!
有有有
You need some fresh air
新鲜空气新鲜空气来了
You'll feel better
水
Water...water...
水有
Stay right there!
神仙水到
This is angel's water
水到渠成
lt'll do you good
现在才第一个回合
This is only the first round, remember
现在才第一个回合呀
What you mean it's just the first round?
是呀 你再捱三个回合
Hold on for another 3 rounds
那老家伙就没力气
the old fart doesn't have it in him
他过来了
l don't think l have either, honest!
糟了 上
Go on, go on! Quick!
好好的打他一顿
Let him have it, kid! Go on, get him!
你想干什么 你不要走过来呀
What're you doing? l'm the referee!
不准打公证人
He's attacking the referee, you must stop him!
打公证人是犯规的
He's not allowed to do that!
你帮我顶住
Go on, do your stuff!
你还不帮我顶住
Go on, don't just stand there watching!
别对老家伙客气
The best defence is attack, remember?
现在又不是开敬老会
Go on, what are you waiting for?
上呀 上呀 快点上 快上
Go on, go ahead!
新鲜空气 新鲜空气
Come here! You need more fresh air
水 水
Water...
Water
这个回合你赢啦
You're doing just fine. l think you won that round
怎么会呢
Why'd you say that?
我做公证人嘛
Because l'm the referee
又来了 快上
Look out, here he comes! Go on!
再接再励
Go on!
锁死他的脚
Try to lock his leg!
千万别让他回气呀
lt's the only way to slow him up!
喝水 喝水
Take this. Go on, you need it!
他又来了 幸亏有第一度防线
At least l have you to protect me!
第三类接触 怎么这么厉害呀
l'm getting too old for this kind of shit!
真有你的 我真服了你
You're doing just great, kid!
我现在才知道
Sitting there, watching you fighting
什么叫做真正的年轻人
it reminded me of me when l was younger!
你何止是打不死
Not only are you unbeatable
简直是永不磨损型
but you're also indestructible!
你不用安慰我了 水 给我水
l'm glad you're so confident
水 有 有
Water...l need water!
水来了
Here's the water. Now drink up
老弟 我绝不会让你渴死的
This should give you a kick, hold tight!
你打到那儿喝到那儿
Don't worry. lt's alright
比神仙还要快乐
lt just has a funny taste
这枝十年的烟袋水 杀菌的
lt's just the water from my pipe, it won't kill you
烟水也是水呀 不过比较苦一点
Bet you feel better, don't you?
来来来 新鲜空气
Here, have some fresh air
你这个金脚带
That was unfair!
不作一声踢我的椰青
Kicking an old age pensioner like that!
挑金不挑银 你倒挺会挑的
lt's pretty smart of you to take all the gold and leave the silver
金价起了嘛
The price of gold nowadays...
真是起得快 跌得快
What goes up must come down again!
打得好 打得好
Good boy! Good boy!
站住
Come here!
兄弟 了不起 了不起
Kid, you were great!
你赢了
You were just great! You're the winner!
这些黄金 我们一人分一半
We'll split the prize 5050
干什么
Stop it! What are you...?
裤带嘛 拿去用吧
You can have my belt if you want it
师父 大师兄回来啦
Master! Brother Jing is coming!
Master, Jing's back!...
师父
Master!
起来 起来 阿龙呢
Get up. get up. Where is Ah Lung?
快点 快点 龙哥在那儿
Brother Lung!... Come on!
师父 我回来啦
Master, l said l'd return
怎么弄成这个样子
Lung, what happened to you?
快抬他回去
Bring him in! Come on, hurry up!